Today, we will be making just a simple bucket
hat.
For this project, I'm going to be using a
5 millimeter hook, a yarn needle, and some
white acrylic yarn.
The first thing we're going to do is make
a magic ring or circle.
So, grab your tail end and hold it at the
bottom of your hand.
Leave a few inches so you can weave it in
nicely.
Grab the top, wrap it around two fingers to
form an X, and then use your hook to go under
and over and pull through.
And then use your two fingers to grab the
loop and remove your fingers and then we're
going to chain two.
To chain, yarn over and pull through.
Again yarn over and then pull through.
And then we're going to do 10 double crochets
into the center of this ring.
And to double crochet, yarn over.
insert your hook into the center of the ring,
yarn over, pull through, yarn over, pull through
just two loops, and then yarn over and pull
through your last two loops.
And then you can tighten the ring by pulling
on the tail end so it's easier to work with.
And again, to double crochet yarn over, insert
your hook, yarn over, pull through, yarn over,
pull through just two loops, and then yarn
over and pull through your last two.
So we're going to do this 8 more times until
we have a total of 10 double crochets.
And now that we are done with our 10 double
crochets, we can pull on the tail end and
close up this little hole.
So, we'll just pull really tight and later
on we'll have to tie into a knot so it doesn't
come loose again.
And now we're going to do a slip stitch into
our very first double crochet.
So just look for the post of our very first
double crochet, make sure you skip the chain
two that we did, and to the right of the post
we're going to go under the 2 loops that make
the V at the top.
And then we're going to yarn over, pull through,
and pull through the loop on our hook and
this is a slip stitch.
And we're going to end every round with a
slip stitch and we are also going to start
every round with a chain two.
So for round two, we're going to chain two
and this round we're going to be doing an
increase in every single stitch.
So an increase is just two double crochets
into one stitch and our first stitch is going
to be that same stitch that we slip stitched
into.
So we're going to yarn over, insert our hook
into that same stitch,
and then we'll complete our double crochet.
And since we're doing an increase in every
stitch, we're going to do one more double
crochet into that same stitch.
Now we're going to move on to the next stitch
and remember to keep going under both loops
that make the V. And we'll do an increase
into every single stitch.
So here we've done 1 and we're going to do
another one into that same stitch.
And we'll do this all the way around and we
should have 20 stitches by the end of this
round.
Now that we've done our 20 double crochets
for round two, we can slip stitch and start
round three with two chains.
And for round three we're going to do an increase
in every second stitch so in the first stitch
we're going to do 1 double crochet, and then
we'll increase in the second stitch
And then we'll continue this pattern of doing
an increase in every second stitch all the
way around.
And for every round that we do increases in
we're always going to end the round with an
increase, so for the very last stitch make
sure that it ends on an increase; otherwise,
it means that you may have counted your stitches
wrong.
And by the end of this round you should have
a total of 30 stitches.
So we're increasing every round by 10.
The first round had 10, the second has 20,
and the third has 30.
And for round 4, we're going to be increasing
in every third stitch.
So last round we did every second.
This one we're going to every third and the
next one we're going to do every fourth.
So fourth round in every third stitch.
So just subtract 1 from the round number and
that's the stitch that you'll be increasing
in.
So we're just going to do 2 double crochets,
and then in the third stitch we're doing 2
double crochets into that same stitch.
But if you do not want to have to count, here's
a little trick that you can do to know where
to increase.
So if you look on your previous round, you
can find the increase and in this stitch right
between those two double crochets of the increase
from last round that is where your increase
for this round will be.
And you can see it here and so you know that
that is where we're going to increase.
So we'll just double crochet until we find
the increase from last round and here it is.
So in between these two double crochets in
that stitch I'm going to do an increase and
this should increase it all the way around
evenly so that we have 10 increases per round.
And if you go back and count it it should
line up with every third stitch and we're
just going to be increasing in this way until
this circle becomes the circumference of our
head.
I found that 7 total rounds would be about
a small, 8 total rounds would be a medium,
and then 9 would be a large.
And I'm just going to be doing a medium.
So fifth round, I'm going to increase in every
fourth stitch and then sixth every fifth stitch
for the seventh round every sixth stitch eighth
round every seventh.
And I've just finished my eight rounds of
increasing and now we're going to stop increasing
and just do one double crochet into every
single stitch all the way around for the next
few rounds.
So again these next few rounds are going to
be just one double crochet into every stitch
but this first round is going to be a little
bit different.
So we'll chain two, and then when we double
crochet we're going to go into the back loops
only.
So if you look from the top there are two
lines that form a V we're going to go in between
them and only go under the back loops when
we do our double crochets.
And again this round has no increases we're
just doing one double crochet into every stitch
in the back loops only.
And you can see that crocheting in the back
loops only forms a sort of fold so this is
the top of the hat where it bends down and
now we're just going to be crocheting the
portion that is between the brim and the top
of the hat.
And it was just for this first round that
we're going under the back loops only.
For the next few rounds, we're going to be
going under both loops and we're going to
do just a few rows until we reached the length
that we want.
And in my case I did 6 more rounds for a total
of 7 between the top of the hat and the start
of the brim.
You can make this shorter or longer if you
want.
So I've done seven total rounds between the
top of the hat and the start of the brim and
you can see that it forms this sort of fold
and we're going to be doing a similar thing
for the brim for the first round for the brim
we're going to be working in the front loops
only so we're going to be folding it a different
direction sort of pop out instead of going
in.
So we're going to be going into the front
loops only.
So again, if you look from the top you can
see the V's and you want to go under the first
loop instead of going through both.
And for the brim we are going to be doing
a little bit of increasing.
We're just going to be picking up where we
left off when we increased the top of the
hat.
So for example, I did 8 rounds for the top
of my hat, and this first round of the brim
(I'm going to call it my ninth round of increasing
which means 9 minus 1), I'm going to increase
in every eighth stitch.
And you can see that going into the front
loops only causes this part to pop out to
start the brim.
And just like we did before every round after
this will not be in the front loops only it
will just be under both loops since we do
not need it to bend anymore.
and I'm going to be alternating in rounds
of increasing and just regular rounds and
then increasing and regular round.
So this next round will be a regular round
with no increases and in the third round of
the brim, I'm going to be doing another increase
round picking up where I left off with the
9th increase round.
So this will be the 10th round of increases
which means 10 minus 1, increase in every
ninth stitch.
And I'm going to be repeating this pattern
until I get the length of the brim that I
want.
And you want to end on an odd number for the
brim because you want to end on an increase
round so the bottom of the brim doesn't curve
in.
So I just did a total of 5 rounds for the
brim just because it is the length of the
brim that I want and you can make it longer
or shorter by adding more rows or less.
Now we can fasten off by chaining one and
cutting off a strand long enough for us to
weave in.
And then we'll use our hook to pull on that
strand of yarn and pull it through and tighten
the knot.
And the last thing to do is weave in all of
our loose ends.
So first, we're going to turn the hat inside
out
and we're going to be weaving in our ends
into the inside of the hat so it's less visible.
We're going to start with the very top and
you want to tighten this as much as you can
and then grab your yarn needle and thread
the yarn through the needle.
And we're going to tie a knot just so it stays
in place and the hole doesn't loosen.
And to tie a knot, I'm just going to go under
a piece of the yarn,
wrap the rest of the tail end around it, and
then pull my yarn needle through and that
should create a knot.
And if you want to do it a second time to
double knot it to really secure it then go
for it.
And then we're going to try to go under as
many stitches as we can in one direction.
So since the stitches are in rounds, I'll
just be going under the stitches in the second
round.
And once I've gone under a few of the stitches,
I'm going to turn around, skip one stitch,
and go under those same stitches once again.
And so if anything tugs on this loose end,
it will have to go in two different directions
and it'll be really secure.
And we can also do this a few more times just
to be really sure that it won't come loose.
Once we're done, we can just cut off the rest
of that loose end and move on to the other
ones.
And where I had to attach a second ball of
yarn, I'm just going to double knot these
two strands together.
So before I start weaving in the loose ends,
i want to be sure that they're knotted and
they won't be coming loose.
And then I'll thread it through my needle
and do the same exact thing where i go under
a few stitches in one direction and turn around
and then go back under those same stitches.
Once everything is weaved in, I can just cut
off all of the extra pieces of yarn and we
should be finished.
So here is the bucket hat!
That is all for this video; I really hope
you enjoyed.
Please leave a like if you did and subscribe
if you're new.
And remember to leave comments if you have
any questions at all.
Thank you so much for watching, I'll see you
next time!